Gurkiran Singh Randhawa

Full-Stack Engineer (UI focused) - Web Applications

Personal Portfolio

Phone: (647) 679 - 0224 | Email: gukiece@gmail.com| https://www.linkedin.com/in/gurkiran4you/ Github: https://github.com/gurkiran4you & https://github.com/gurkiran

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with 10+ years of experience delivering scalable web applications with an emphasis on frontend architecture and user experience. Specialized in modernizing legacy platforms, improving development workflows, building enterprise-scale apps for healthcare, telecom and finance industries.

KEY SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, php, NodeJS, Deno, Angular, React, JQuery, Lodash

FE/Web technologies: HTML, CSS, SCSS, HTTP, I18n, Web-socket, Browser APIs

Databases: SQLite, SQLServer, MongoDB(Mongoose)

Other: TeamCity, Jira Workflows, CI/CD Scripts, Google Cloud, Github Actions, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer- Web Applications

(July 2019 - End of May 2024)

Circle Cardiovascular Imaging , Calgary, AB, Canada

- Migrated legacy AngularJS to Angular 17, reducing tech debt and improving load times by 35%.
- Architected frontend patterns adopted across a 30+ dev team, boosting UI consistency and reusability by ~50%.
- Delivered a dynamic WYSIWYG report editor used in 1M+ clinical reports annually.
- Automated localization pipeline with Python scripts, cutting translation effort by 40% and improving turnaround by 3x.
- Implemented template-driven reporting, enabling hospitals to configure reports and saving 20+ hours per release.
- Reduced PDF generation latency by 60% through optimized frontend/backend integration.
- Shipped cross-platform installers (Windows, Mac, Linux) used by OEM partners GE and Siemens.

Web Developer

(Sept 2018 – Nov 2018)

Fidelity Investments, Merrimack, NH, USA

- Worked on building an Onboarding portal for current and prospective hires using React
- Made the CSS modular by using SCSS features such as mixins, placeholders, functions etc.
- Developed Swagger API using NodeJS, as a mockup for the Java Backend team to speed up their development

Web Developer (Sep 2017-Sep 2018)

Comcast Corporation, Philadelphia, USA

- Developed the agent-facing Xfinity Mobile web app using Angular 5/6, Bootstrap, and SCSS to manage customer services and lines (up to 5 per account).
- Replaced the legacy Zendesk-based system with a modern, scalable frontend and integrated RESTful and GraphQL APIs via Node.js.
- Optimized Webpack config, reducing development build time from 2 minutes to 20 seconds.

Web Developer

(July 2016 – July 2017)

AARP, Washington DC, USA

- Migrated legacy AngularJS 1.2 components to 1.5 and made them responsive for mobile compatibility.
- Contributed to building a proof-of-concept homepage using React, Gulp, and modular SCSS.
- Supported daily content updates and feature parity with AARP's live production site.

EDUCATION